Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
Happy New Year.
新年快乐。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
Happy New Year.
新年快乐。
Happy New Year, Marco.
新年快乐，Marco。
It's December 31st and we are on New Year's Eve.
今天是12月31日，我们正在过新年前夜。
That's right.
没错。
And since it's New Year's Eve, we're talking about New Year's resolutions.
既然是除夕，我们就来谈谈新年决心。
Right.
对。
In many places, it's very common to make a promise for the New Year, something that you
在很多地方，人们通常会为新年许下一个承诺，一个你
will change.
会改变的事情。
Yes.
是的。
A promise to yourself.
对自己的承诺。
To yourself.
对自己。
To change something.
去改变一些事情。
And that's what our dialogue is about today.
这就是我们今天对话的主题。
So why don't we take a look at our vocabulary preview for this lesson.
那么我们先来看看这节课的词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay.
好的。
On vocabulary preview today, we only have one word.
今天的词汇预览，我们只有一个词。
Eating habits.
饮食习惯。
So what are eating habits?
那么什么是饮食习惯？
The regular way you eat.
你通常的饮食方式。
Right.
对。
So if you eat healthy or if you eat lots of unhealthy food.
比如你吃得健康，或者你吃很多不健康的食物。
Or even maybe what time you eat, right?
甚至可能是什么时候吃，对吧？
If you eat every day a certain time.
如果你每天在固定时间吃饭。
Yeah.
嗯。
Eating habits.
饮食习惯。
Okay.
好的。
So we're ready to listen to our dialogue today and it's going to be a little bit fast, but
那我们准备听今天的对话了，语速会有点快，但
don't worry about it.
别担心。
We'll come back and explain all of the key vocabulary after.
之后我们会回来解释所有关键词汇。
So did I tell you about my New Year's resolution?
我跟你说了我的新年决心吗？
I've decided to go on a diet.
我决定节食。
And you're going to completely transform your eating habits, right?
你要彻底改变你的饮食习惯，对吧？
Exactly.
正是。
I'm going to cut out all the junk I eat.
我要戒掉所有我吃的垃圾食品。
No more chips.
再也不吃薯片了。
No more soda.
再也不喝汽水了。
No more fried food.
再也不吃油炸食品了。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
I've heard this one before.
这话我以前听过。
But this time, I'm going to stick to it.
但这次我会坚持到底。
I really mean it.
我是认真的。
Trust me, Carol.
相信我，卡罗尔。
I'm going to be a new man in one year's time.
一年后我会变成一个全新的人。
Well, I guess we'll just have to wait and see.
嗯，我想我们只能拭目以待了。
Thanks, honey.
谢谢，亲爱的。
That was a great meal.
这顿饭太棒了。
I'm stuffed.
我吃撑了。
Do we have any chips left?
我们还有薯片吗？
So Marco, do you think this guy will be successful in changing his eating habits?
那么马可，你觉得这家伙能成功改变饮食习惯吗？
Well, I guess he'll never change, but this gives us a great opportunity to look at some
嗯，我猜他永远改不了，但这给了我们一个很好的机会，在语言点部分学习一些
great vocabulary in this lesson in Language Takeaway.
很棒的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言点。
Our first word on Language Takeaway is junk.
语言点的第一个词是 junk。
Junk.
Junk。
So junk comes from junk food.
所以 junk 来自 junk food。
Exactly.
没错。
Unhealthy food.
不健康的食物。
Yeah.
对。
Like cheese, chips.
比如奶酪、薯片。
Hamburgers.
汉堡包。
Yeah.
对。
All that junk.
所有那些垃圾食品。
Okay.
好的。
Our second word for Language Takeaway, transform.
语言点的第二个词是 transform。
Transform.
Transform。
Meaning?
什么意思？
To change.
改变。
Yep.
对。
Change.
改变。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
So this guy is going to transform his eating habits.
所以这家伙要改变他的饮食习惯。
He's going to change his eating habits.
他要改变他的饮食习惯。
Yeah.
是的。
Our third word is...
我们的第三个词是……
Stuffed.
吃饱了。
I'm stuffed.
我吃饱了。
So we have some great examples on how we can use stuffed and you'll get the meaning from
我们有一些很好的例子来说明如何使用“stuffed”，你会从中理解它的意思。
it.
它。
Example one.
例子一。
Come on.
来吧。
Have one more piece of cake.
再吃一块蛋糕。
Oh, I can't.
哦，我吃不下了。
I'm stuffed.
我吃饱了。
Example two.
例子二。
Oh, I ate way too much.
哦，我吃得太多了。
I'm stuffed.
我吃饱了。
Okay.
好的。
I'm stuffed.
我吃饱了。
The feeling you get if you eat too much food.
就是你吃太多东西时的感觉。
Right.
对。
I'm full.
我饱了。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好了。
So these are some great words that you can use talking about food.
这些是你在谈论食物时可以用的好词。
And eating habits.
和饮食习惯。
And now we can listen to our dialogue a second time and this time, like always, it's going
现在我们可以再听一遍对话，这次，像往常一样，会慢速播放。
to be slow.
慢速。
So did I tell you about my New Year's resolution?
我跟你说了我的新年决心吗？
I've decided to go on a diet.
我决定节食。
And you're going to completely transform your eating habits, right?
你要彻底改变你的饮食习惯，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
I'm going to cut out all that junk I eat.
我要戒掉所有那些垃圾食品。
No more chips.
不再吃薯片。
No more soda.
不再喝汽水。
No more fried food.
不再吃油炸食品。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
I've heard this one before.
这话我以前听过。
But this time I'm going to stick to it.
但这次我会坚持到底。
I really mean it.
我是认真的。
Trust me, Carol.
相信我，卡罗尔。
I'm going to be a new man in one year's time.
一年后我会变成一个全新的人。
Well, I guess we'll just have to wait and see.
嗯，我想我们只能拭目以待了。
Thanks, honey.
谢谢，亲爱的。
That was a great meal.
这顿饭真棒。
I'm stuffed.
我吃撑了。
Do we have any chips left?
我们还有薯片吗？
There's a lot of great language in this dialogue, isn't there?
这段对话里有很多很棒的语言点，对吧？
Yeah, a lot of great language that we can take a look at with our Fluency Builder.
是啊，很多很棒的语言点，我们可以用流利度构建器来学习。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
The first phrase we have for you is...
我们要介绍的第一个短语是……
Stick to it.
坚持到底。
Yes.
是的。
We've got some examples of how this phrase is used.
我们有一些这个短语用法的例子。
So let's listen.
我们来听听。
Example 1.
例子1。
Quitting smoking is so hard.
戒烟太难了。
Stick to it.
坚持住。
It's good for you.
这对你有好处。
Example 2.
例子2。
I can't solve this math problem.
我解不出这道数学题。
Stick to it.
坚持住。
I'm sure you'll get it.
我相信你一定能做出来。
So stick to it, right?
所以要坚持，对吧？
Basically means keep doing it.
基本上就是继续做下去的意思。
Right.
对。
Even though English learning can be hard...
即使学英语很难……
You should stick to it.
你也应该坚持。
Stick to it.
坚持。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, let's look at our second phrase for Fluency Builder.
好了，我们来看流利度构建器的第二个短语。
I mean it.
我是认真的。
Mean it.
认真的。
So this is a great way of saying...
所以这是一种很好的表达方式……
I'm serious.
我是认真的。
Yeah.
是的。
I mean it.
我是说真的。
I'm not joking.
我不是在开玩笑。
I'm not joking, right?
我不是在开玩笑，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And our final phrase in Fluency Builder.
这是我们流利度构建中的最后一个短语。
Cut out.
Cut out。
Again, we've got some examples of this phrase as native speakers use it.
同样，我们有一些母语者使用这个短语的例子。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example 1.
例子1。
You have to cut out the salt from your diet.
你必须从饮食中戒掉盐。
No more chips.
不能再吃薯片了。
No more french fries.
不能再吃薯条了。
No more popcorn.
不能再吃爆米花了。
Example 2.
例子2。
It's time for me to focus on my work.
是时候专注于我的工作了。
I'm going to cut out everything else from my life.
我要把生活中其他的一切都排除掉。
Okay, so cut out means...
好的，所以 cut out 的意思是……
To remove.
去除。
Completely remove.
完全去除。
Take it away.
拿掉。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, some great language, some great phrases in our dialogue today.
好的，今天的对话中有一些很棒的语言和短语。
So why don't we listen to it a third time and we'll come back in a little bit.
那我们再听一遍，一会儿再回来。
So did I tell you about my New Year's resolution?
我跟你说了我的新年决心吗？
I've decided to go on a diet.
我决定要节食。
And you're going to completely transform your eating habits, right?
你要彻底改变你的饮食习惯，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
I'm going to cut out all the junk I eat.
我要戒掉所有我吃的垃圾食品。
No more chips.
不能再吃薯片了。
No more soda.
不能再喝汽水了。
No more fried food.
不能再吃油炸食品了。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
I've heard this one before.
这话我以前听过。
But this time, I'm going to stick to it.
但这次我会坚持到底。
I really mean it.
我是认真的。
Trust me, Carol, I'm going to be a new man in one year's time.
相信我，卡罗尔，一年后我会变成一个全新的人。
Well, I guess we'll just have to wait and see.
嗯，我想我们只能拭目以待了。
Thanks, honey.
谢谢，亲爱的。
That was a great meal.
这顿饭真棒。
I'm stuffed.
我吃撑了。
Do we have any chips left?
我们还有薯片吗？
Okay so New Year's resolutions, a really common and popular thing in North America.
好的，新年决心在北美非常普遍和流行。
It's tradition to make a promise to yourself on New Year's and stick to it throughout the
传统上，人们会在新年对自己许下承诺，并坚持
whole year.
一整年。
Right.
没错。
But the funny thing is that very few people actually stick to their New Year's resolution.
但有趣的是，很少有人能真正坚持他们的新年决心。
That's true.
确实如此。
The most common ones are I'm going to quit smoking.
最常见的决心是“我要戒烟”。
That never happens.
那从来不会实现。
I'm going to go on a diet.
“我要节食”。
Like this guy.
就像这家伙。
I'm going to quit drinking.
“我要戒酒”。
That almost never happens either.
那也几乎从没实现过。
On New Year's Eve, you start drinking.
除夕夜，你开始喝酒。
I mean, it's a bad time.
我是说，那可不是好时机。
Come on.
得了吧。
And another really common one is I'm going to join a gym.
另一个非常常见的是“我要去健身房”。
That's why gym membership sales are so high in January.
这就是为什么一月份健身房会员销量那么高。
Right.
没错。
Everyone joins a gym in January.
每个人一月份都去办健身卡。
But come February, very few people in the gym.
但到了二月，健身房里几乎没人了。
Yeah.
是啊。
So Marco, do you have a New Year's resolution for this year?
那么马可，你今年有新年决心吗？
Yes, I have a New Year's resolution and I resolve to continue bringing everyone some
是的，我有一个新年决心，我决心继续为大家带来
great lessons.
精彩的课程。
Oh, that's so good.
哦，那太好了。
And I think I can stick to that one.
而且我觉得我能坚持这个。
Yes.
是的。
Well, I do hope that you do stick to that one, Marco.
嗯，我真希望你能坚持那个，马可。
We will.
我们会坚持的。
But today we're out of time.
但今天时间不够了。
So please go to our website and leave all your questions and comments at EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问我们的网站，在EnglishPod.com留下你的问题和评论。
And we'll see you there.
我们那里见。
But until then, it's goodbye.
但在此之前，再见。
Bye.
再见。